<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>devops on Oleksandr Kulbida</title>
    <link>https://okulbida.com/tags/devops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in devops on Oleksandr Kulbida</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0300</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://okulbida.com/tags/devops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Best Practices: Code Organization and Structure</title>
      <link>https://okulbida.com/posts/terraform-code-organization-best-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 14:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okulbida.com/posts/terraform-code-organization-best-practices/</guid>
      <description>Essential Terraform best practices for organizing and structuring your infrastructure code:
1. Separate Configuration Files
Instead of putting all code in main.tf, distribute it across multiple files:
 main.tf: Calls modules, locals, and data sources to create all resources variables.tf: Contains variable declarations used in main.tf. Place required variables at the top and optional ones at the bottom, separated by a comment line for better readability outputs.tf: Contains outputs from resources created in main.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How GitHub Engineers Tackle Platform Problems</title>
      <link>https://okulbida.com/posts/github-platform-engineering-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 00:30:00 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://okulbida.com/posts/github-platform-engineering-approaches/</guid>
      <description>GitHub&amp;rsquo;s platform engineering team shares their approach to tackling infrastructure challenges at scale. Key strategies include:
Understanding your domain:
 Talk to neighboring teams with more experience Investigate old issues to understand system limitations Read documentation to build foundational knowledge  Platform-specific skills:
 Network fundamentals (TCP, UDP, L4 load balancing, debugging tools) Operating systems and hardware selection for scalability and cost Infrastructure as Code (Terraform, Ansible, Consul) Distributed systems understanding (failures are inevitable, need failover/recovery)  Impact radius considerations:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
